<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<recipe>
    <l>Cheese Straws</l>
    <l>Stacey Triplette</l>

    <l>This is my Nana's cheese straw recipe. <person>Nancy Frances Seats Sisk</person> was born in
            <year>1928</year> in </l>
    <l><place>Lewisville, NC</place> to a family that owned a small farm and a Mom and Pop store
        (literally: my great-</l>
    <l>grandparents were actually known to customers and family as Mom and Pop). This is my </l>
    <l>great grandmother <person>Ethel Seats</person>'s recipe modified by my grandmother (called
        Frances or Fanny) for the <date>1950s-1970s</date> taste </l>
    <l>for processed food. For that era, everything from a national brand seemed better than local </l>
    <l>alternatives. Cheese straws are a <place>Winston-Salem, NC</place> favorite.
            <description>They are spicy cheese cookies</description>, </l>
    <l>bizarre but delicious. I grew up eating cheese straws as party snacks, particularly around
        Christmas. </l>
    <l>Nana gives my dad, <person>Richard K. Triplette</person> (<date>born 1952</date>) a full
        Tupperware container of these every Christmas as his present.</l>
    <alternate>
        <l>When I make this recipe hipster style, I substitute unsalted butter for the Parkay and
            replace the Kraft cheese with the nicest, sharpest cheddar I can find. I reduce cooking
            time to 10 minutes, and I quadruple the recipe to </l>
        <l>get a full tupperware container. Instead of red pepper flakes I use Sriracha or my
            hometown hot </l>
    </alternate>
    <l>sauce, Texas Pete, made in Winston-Salem, NC. My grandmother wrote this <dimension>3 X 5 recipe card</dimension> </l>
    <l>around <year>1980</year> and gave it to me at Christmas in <year>2014</year>. I took this photo to prove to Nana that I </l>
    <l>could make her recipe my way and it would look exactly the same. Note Nana's <method>handwriting</method>. </l>
    <l>It's very typical for her era, and she was known to have only average penmanship. Nana </l>
    <l>graduated from a Winston-Salem high school at a time when this was a major accomplishment, </l>
    <l>especially for a woman from a rural family. Some of the girls among my Nana's <number>eleven</number> siblings
        graduated </l>
    <l>high school, but only <number>one</number> of the boys, her younger brother Worth, was allowed to stay in
        school. He eventually</l>
    <l>became a high school teacher. Nana's other brothers worked on the farm and then joined the
        army, leaving school around the sixth grade. Nana worked as a hairstylist from the <dates>1950's up
        until c. 2000</dates>. She married my grandfather, <person>Victor Sisk</person>, who did not have a high school
        degree. Victor served as an army radio operator during WWI and afterward found a job as
        plant manager in a typical</l>
    <l>a textile company, The Salem Company (later Lucia). My mom, <person>Kathy Sisk Triplette</person>, born <year>1951</year>,
        is their first of two daughters. </l>
</recipe>
