
<!DOCTYPE html
  SYSTEM "about:legacy-compat">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
   <head>
      <meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html; charset=utf-8" />
   </head>
   <body>
      <ol>
         <li>Archives Holding Mitford’s Papers <ul>
               <li>Baylor University, Armstrong Browning Library</li>
               <li>Berkshire Record Office</li>
               <li>British Library</li>
               <li>Boston Public Library</li>
               <li>Cambridge University: Fitzwilliam Museum</li>
               <li>Duke University Rubenstein Library</li>
               <li>Eton College</li>
               <li>Florida State University Special Collections</li>
               <li>The Women’s Library, Glasgow</li>
               <li>Houghton Library, Harvard</li>
               <li>Huntington Library</li>
               <li>University of Iowa Special Collections</li>
               <li>Massachusetts Historical Society</li>
               <li>New York Public Library</li>
               <li>Oxford University, Balliol College Archives</li>
               <li>Oxford University, Bodleian Library</li>
               <li>Reading Central Library</li>
               <li>John Ruskin Library, Lancaster</li>
               <li>The John Rylands Library</li>
               <li>National Library of Scotland, Manuscript Collections</li>
               <li>University of Texas, Ransom Center</li>
               <li>University of Reading Special Collections</li>
               <li>University of Virginia Special Collections</li>
               <li>Wellesley College, Margaret Clapp Library, Special Collections</li>
               <li>Wordsworth Trust</li>
               <li>Yale University, Beineke Library</li>
            </ul>
         </li>
         <li>Organizations Relevant to Mitford’s World <ul>
               <li>Americans</li>
               <li>Billiard Club</li>
               <li>House of Bourbon</li>
               <li>Cavaliers</li>
               <li>Court of Chancery</li>
               <li>Church of England</li>
               <li>Clarendon Press</li>
               <li>the Cockney School</li>
               <li>Court of King’s Bench</li>
               <li>Drover family</li>
               <li>Eton College</li>
               <li>Hampden Club</li>
               <li>High Court of JusticeCommissioners of the High Court of JusticeCommissioners</li>
               <li>Holland House circleHolland House set</li>
               <li>House of Commons</li>
               <li>House of Lords</li>
               <li>Italians</li>
               <li>The Society of Jesus</li>
               <li>the Kembles</li>
               <li>Marylebone Cricket Club</li>
               <li>House of Medici</li>
               <li>Minerva Press</li>
               <li> Mitford </li>
               <li>Mr.and Mrs.Mitford</li>
               <li>the Moncks, family of John Berkeley Monck </li>
               <li>Members of Parliament </li>
               <li>New Model Army</li>
               <li>Palmerite</li>
               <li>the Parfitt’s</li>
               <li>Parliament</li>
               <li>Court of Pope Pius VII</li>
               <li>PrelacyPrelates</li>
               <li>the Presybterian factionPeace Party</li>
               <li>Privy Council</li>
               <li>Richmond Coach or Stage</li>
               <li>Royal Academy of Arts</li>
               <li>the people of ScotlandScotchScotsScotchmen</li>
               <li>Scriblerus ClubScriblerians</li>
               <li> Slade </li>
               <li>Taylor and Hessey</li>
               <li>Tory Party</li>
               <li>Twickenham Coach or Stage</li>
               <li> Valpy the Valpys </li>
               <li> Webb </li>
               <li>Weylandite</li>
               <li>the Whig party</li>
            </ul>
         </li>
         <li>Fictional Groups Referenced by Mitford <ul>
               <li>Attendants &amp;c.</li>
               <li>Balfours of Burleys</li>
               <li>the Bustling Dame’s children </li>
               <li>Chorus</li>
               <li>Citizens</li>
               <li>the Danaides</li>
               <li>Guards</li>
               <li>Guards</li>
               <li>Ladies</li>
               <li>Nobles</li>
               <li>Nobles</li>
               <li>officers in Charles I </li>
               <li>Prelates</li>
            </ul>
         </li>
         <li>Reference Works Published in the 19th Century <ul>
               <li>Notes on a Journey in America, from the Coast of Virginia to the Territory of
                  Illinois </li>
               <li>the Bill of Rights</li>
               <li>Account of the Captivity of Robert Knox and Other Englishmen, in the Island of
                  Ceylon: And of the Captain’s Miraculous Escape and Return to England in September
                  1680, After Detention on the Island of Nineteen Years and a Half </li>
               <li>Travels in Various Countries of Europe, Asia and Africa. Part the third, section
                  the first: Scandinavia </li>
               <li>Collectanea Curiosa, or Miscellaneous Tracts: Relating to the History and
                  Antiquities of England and Ireland, the Universities of Oxford and Cambridge, and
                  a Variety of Other Subjects </li>
               <li>The Compleat Angler, or, The Contemplative Man’s Recreation: Being a Discourse of
                  Rivers, and Fish-ponds, and Fish and Fishing: Not Unworthy the Perusal of Most
                  Anglers </li>
               <li>Rural Sports</li>
               <li>Encyclopedia Metropolitana; or, Universal Dictionary of Knowledge (30 vols.,
                  1817-1845) </li>
               <li>A History of the Municipal Church of St. Lawrence, Reading</li>
               <li>Letters from Illinois: Illustrated by a Map of the United States, Shewing Mr.
                  Birkbeck’s Journey from Norfolk to Illinois and a Map of English Prairie and the
                  Adjacent Country by John Melish </li>
               <li>Lives of the English Poets</li>
               <li>Lectures on the English Comic Writers, delivered at the Surry Institution </li>
               <li>Letters Written by Eminent Persons in the Seventeenth and Eighteenth Centuries:
                  To Which are Added, Hearne’s Journeys to Reading, and to Whaddon Hall, the Seat of
                  Browne Willis, Esq., and Lives of Eminent Men by John Aubrey, Esq., the Whole Now
                  First Published from the Originals </li>
               <li>Memoirs of John Duke of Marlborough: With His Original Correspondence; Collected
                  from the Family Records at Blenheim, and Other Authentic Sources. Illustrated with
                  Portraits, Maps, and Military Plans. </li>
               <li>Some Account of the Life of Rachael Wriothesley, Lady Russell, by the editor of
                  Madam Du Deffand’s letters. Followed by a series of letters from Lady Russell to
                  her husband, William, Lord Russell; from 1672 to 1682; together with some
                  miscellaneous letters to and from Lady Russell. To which are added, eleven letters
                  from Dorothy Sidney, Countess of Sunderland, to George Saville, Marquis of
                  Hallifax, in the year 1680 </li>
               <li>The Literary Pocket Book, or Companion for the Lover of Art and Nature </li>
               <li>Naturalis Historiæ</li>
               <li>The New Whig Guide</li>
               <li>Post Office Directory of Berkshire, Northamptonshire, and Oxfordshire; with
                  Bedfordshire, Buckinghamshire, and Huntingdonshire </li>
               <li>The Post Office Directory of Berkshire, Northamptonshire, Oxfordshire, with
                  Bedfordshire, Buckinghamshire, and Huntingdonshire </li>
               <li>Shakespeare and His Times: Including the Biography of the Poet; Criticisms on his
                  Genius and Writings; A New Chronology of the Plays; A Disquisition on the Object
                  of His Sonnets; And a History of the Manners, Customs, and Amusements,
                  Superstitions, Poetry, and Elegant Literature of His Age </li>
               <li>Sketches of America: a Narrative of a Journey of Five Thousand Miles Through the
                  Eastern and Western States of America; Contained in Eight Reports Addressed to the
                  Thirty-nine English Families by whom the Author was Deputed, in June 1817, to
                  Ascertain Whether Any, and What Part of the United States Would be Suitable for
                  Their Residence. With Remarks on Mr. Birkbeck’s Notes and Letters </li>
               <li>Anecdotes, Observations, and Characters of Books and Men. Collected from the
                  Conversation of Mr. Pope, and Other Eminent Persons of His Time </li>
               <li>A Narrative of a Ten Years’ Residence at Tripoli in Africa from the Original
                  Correspondence in the Possession of the Family of the Late Richard Tully, Esq.,
                  Comprising Authentic Memoirs and Anecdotes of the Reigning Bashaw, His Family, and
                  Other Persons of Distinction; also an Account of the Domestic Manners of the
                  Moors, Arabs, and Turks </li>
               <li>Travels through Sweden, Finland, and Lapland to the North Cape, in the Years 1798
                  and 1799. </li>
               <li>Travels to Discover the Source of the Nile, In the Years 1768, 1769, 1770, 1771
                  1772, and 1773 </li>
               <li>A Visit To Paris in 1814: Being a Review of the Moral, Political, Intellectual,
                  and Social Condition of the French Capital </li>
               <li>Letters from the Hon. Horace Walpole to George Montagu, Esq. from the year 1736,
                  to the year 1770: Now First Published from the Originals in the Possession of the
                  Editor </li>
               <li>The Lives of Dr. John Donne, Sir Henry Wotton, Mr. Richard Hooker, Mr. George
                  Herbert and Dr. Robert Sanderson. </li>
               <li>A Descriptive Account of the Mansion and Gardens of White-Knights: A Seat of His
                  Grace the Duke of Marlborough. By Mrs. Hofland. Illustrated with twenty-three
                  engravings, from pictures taken on the spot by T.C. Hofland </li>
            </ul>
         </li>
         <li>19th-Century Periodicals <ul>
               <li>The Anti-Jacobin, or Weekly Examiner</li>
               <li>Berkshire Chronicle</li>
               <li>Blackwood’s Magazine</li>
               <li>Edinburgh Review, second series</li>
               <li>The Examiner</li>
               <li>John Bull</li>
               <li>The Lady’s Magazine</li>
               <li>The Lady’s Magazine; or Entertaining Companion for the Fair Sex, appropriated
                  solely for their Use and Amusement. [series 1.] </li>
               <li>The Lady’s Magazine; or Entertaining Companion for the Fair Sex, appropriated
                  solely for their Use and Amusement. [series 2, vol. 1-3] </li>
               <li>The Lady’s Magazine; or Mirror of the Belle-Lettres, Fine Arts, Fashions, Music,
                  Drama, &amp;c. [series 2, vol. 4-10] </li>
               <li>Lady’s Monthly Museum; Or, Polite Repository of Amusement and Instruction </li>
               <li>An Englishwoman’s Letter to Mrs. Hannah More on the Present Crisis </li>
               <li>The Literary Gazette, and Journal of Belles Lettres, Arts, Sciences</li>
               <li>The London Magazine</li>
               <li>The Museum; or Record of Literature, Fine Arts, Antiquities, the Drama, &amp;c. </li>
               <li>New Monthly Magazine</li>
               <li>The Observer</li>
               <li>Panoramic Miscellany, and Review of Literature, Science, Arts, Inventions and
                  Occurrences </li>
               <li>The Political Register</li>
               <li>Quarterly Review</li>
               <li>The Reading Mercury and Oxford Gazette, etc.</li>
               <li>"Mr. Haydon’s Raising of Lazarus"</li>
               <li>The Iris</li>
               <li>The Spectator</li>
               <li>The Tatler</li>
               <li>The Times</li>
               <li>Timothy Trueman’s Admonitions to the Clergy, Respecting Tithes: First Published
                  in a Letter Inserted in the Statesman Newspaper, and Now Reprinted with Several
                  Corrections and Additions, Particularly an Introduction </li>
               <li>The Curse of Gehazi, or, Leprosy of Corruption: Exemplified in a Narrative of the
                  Life of Robert Watkins, alias Robert Turner Watkins, alias Bribery Bob, Who was
                  Executed on the 30th of July Last, for the Robbery and Murder of Mr. Stephen
                  Rodway, Late of Cricklade, in Whitshire </li>
               <li>A Letter to the Independent Electors of Westminster, as it Appeared in the
                  Independent Whig of Sunday, May 21, 1809 </li>
            </ul>
         </li>
         <li>Literary Works <ul>
               <li>55 Days</li>
               <li>The Abbot</li>
               <li>The Absentee</li>
               <li>The Works of Virgil, in Latin and English. The original Text correctly printed
                  from the most authentic Editions, collated for this Purpose. The Æneid Translated
                  By the Rev. Mr. Christopher Pitt, The Eclogues and Georgics, with Notes on the
                  Whole, By the Rev. Mr. Joseph Warton. With several New Observations By Mr.
                  Holdsworth, Mr. Spence, and Others. Also, A Dissertation on the Sixth Book of the
                  Æneid, by Mr. Warburton. On the Shield of Æneas, by Mr. W. Whitehead. On the
                  Character of Japis, by the late Dr. Atterbury, Bishop of Rochester. And, Three
                  Essays on Pastoral, Didactic and Epic Poetry, by the Editor </li>
               <li>The Aeneid</li>
               <li>The Æneid of Virgil, translated into blank verse by J. Beresford</li>
               <li>The Aeneid</li>
               <li>The Tragedies of Aeschylus</li>
               <li>Agamemnon</li>
               <li>Aladdin</li>
               <li>Alcestis</li>
               <li>All for Love</li>
               <li>All’s Well that Ends Well</li>
               <li>Antigone</li>
               <li>The Antiquary</li>
               <li>Arabian Tales; or, A Continuation of the Arabian Nights Entertainments,
                  consisting of stories related by the Sultana of the Indies, newly tr[anslated]
                  from the original Arabic into French by Dom Chavis and Cazotte; and tr[anslated]
                  from the French into English, by Robert Heron </li>
               <li>As You Like It</li>
               <li>Athalie</li>
               <li>Atherton, and Other Tales</li>
               <li>Beauty</li>
               <li>The fable of the bees, or, Private vices, public benefits : containing several
                  discourses to demonstrate that human frailties, during the degeneracy of mankind,
                  may be turn’d to the advantage of the civil society, and made to supply the place
                  of moral virtues. </li>
               <li>Belford Regis; or, Sketches of a Country Town</li>
               <li>Bertram; or, The Castle of St. Aldobrand: a tragedy, in five acts</li>
               <li>Christian Bible</li>
               <li>The Holy Bible Newly Translated from the Original Hebrew: with Notes Critical and
                  Explanatory </li>
               <li>Blanch: A Poem in Four Cantos</li>
               <li>Bluebeard, or Female Curiosity: a Dramatic Romance in Three Acts</li>
               <li>Bonduca</li>
               <li>The Bride of Lammermoor</li>
               <li>Camilla, or a Picture of Young Lady</li>
               <li>Cecilia; or Memoirs of an Heiress</li>
               <li>Charles the First; An Historical Tragedy, in Five Acts</li>
               <li>The History of the Reign of the Emperor Charles V</li>
               <li>The history of Sir Charles Grandison: In a series of letters published from the
                  originals, by the editor of Pamela and Clarissa. </li>
               <li>Childe Harold’s Pilgrimage</li>
               <li>Choephoræ</li>
               <li>Christina, The Maid of the South Seas; A Poem</li>
               <li>The Cid (1637)</li>
               <li>Cinna (1643)</li>
               <li>The City Wives’ Confederacy</li>
               <li>Clarissa, or, The history of a young lady : comprehending the most important
                  concerns of private life: and particularly shewing, the distresses that may attend
                  the misconduct both of parents and children, in relation to marriage </li>
               <li>Claudia’s Dream</li>
               <li>the Code of Alfred</li>
               <li>Coeur de Lion; or the Third Crusade. A Poem in 16 books. (historical epic, 1822) </li>
               <li>Confessions of an English Opium-Eater</li>
               <li>Corinne, ou, L’Italie</li>
               <li>Coriolanus</li>
               <li>Tales of Fancy: Country Neighbors, or, The Secret</li>
               <li>Country Stories</li>
               <li>The Critic: or, a Tragedy Rehearsed</li>
               <li>The Travels of Cyllenius: A Poem, in 66 cantos</li>
               <li>Cymbeline</li>
               <li>Deaf and Dumb </li>
               <li>Deaf as a Post (Drury Lane, 1823)</li>
               <li>The Decline and Fall of the Roman Empire</li>
               <li>Discipline: A Novel</li>
               <li>Don Juan</li>
               <li>El ingenioso hidalgo don Quijote de la Mancha</li>
               <li>Don Sebastian</li>
               <li>The Dramatic Works of Mary Russell Mitford</li>
               <li>Dramatic Scenes, Sonnets, and Other Poems</li>
               <li>Emily, A Dramatic Sketch</li>
               <li>Emma: A Novel</li>
               <li>Endymion</li>
               <li>Epilogue to Orestes by Euripides</li>
               <li>The Essays of Elia</li>
               <li>Eunice</li>
               <li>An Account of the European Settlements in America, in six parts</li>
               <li>Evelina: Or, The History of a Young Lady’s Entrance Into the World</li>
               <li>The Faerie Queene</li>
               <li>The Faithful Shepherdess</li>
               <li>Fiesco</li>
               <li>Die Verschwörung des Fiesco zu Genua; or Fiesco’s Conspiracy at Genoa </li>
               <li>Fingal: An Ancient Epic Poem, in Six Books: Together with Several Other Poems,
                  Composed by Ossian the Son of Fingal. Translated from the Galic Language, by James
                  Macpherson. </li>
               <li>Florence Macarthy: An Irish Tale</li>
               <li>Foscari: A Tragedy</li>
               <li>Fragments of Ancient Poetry Collected in the Highlands of Scotland, and
                  Translated from the Galic or Erse Language </li>
               <li>The Fudge Family in Paris</li>
               <li>Gammer Gurton’s Needle</li>
               <li> Gaston de Blondeville</li>
               <li>Gaston de Blondeville</li>
               <li>Glenarvon</li>
               <li>Glenfergus. In Three Volumes</li>
               <li>Travels into Several Remote Nations of the World. In Four Parts. By Lemuel
                  Gulliver, First a Surgeon, and then a Captain of Several Ships </li>
               <li>Guy Mannering</li>
               <li>Halidon Hill; A Dramatic Sketch from Scottish History</li>
               <li>Hamlet</li>
               <li>The Tragedy of Charles I</li>
               <li>Benjamin Robert Haydon: Correspondence and Table-Talk</li>
               <li>Lectures on the English Comic Writers</li>
               <li>Lectures on the Dramatic Literature of the Age of Elizabeth</li>
               <li>The Heiress</li>
               <li>Helen</li>
               <li>Henry IV, part one</li>
               <li>Henry IV, part two</li>
               <li>Henry V</li>
               <li>Henry VIII</li>
               <li>History of the Reigns of Edward and Richard II</li>
               <li>The History of England</li>
               <li>Memoirs of the Late Thomas Holcroft, Written by Himself and Continued to the Time
                  of His Death </li>
               <li>The Honeymoon</li>
               <li>Horace (1640)</li>
               <li>Hudibras</li>
               <li>Human Life: A Poem</li>
               <li>The Expedition of Humphrey Clinker</li>
               <li>The Hypocrite</li>
               <li>The Iliad</li>
               <li>Journal of a Residence in India: illustrated by engravings</li>
               <li>Inez de Castro; A Tragedy in Five Acts</li>
               <li>Inferno</li>
               <li>The Invariable Principles of Poetry, in a Letter Addressed to Thomas Campbell,
                  Esq.; Occasioned by Some Critical Observations in his Specimens of British Poets,
                  Particularly Relating to the Poetical Character of Pope. </li>
               <li>Ion</li>
               <li>Ion</li>
               <li>Ivanhoe</li>
               <li>John Bull the Englishman’s Fireside, a Comedy in five acts.</li>
               <li>The Gospel of John</li>
               <li>Julian; a Tragedy in Five Acts</li>
               <li>The Curse of Kehama: A Poem in Two Volumes</li>
               <li>Kenilworth</li>
               <li>The Life and Death of King John</li>
               <li>King John, an Historical Tragedy, Altered from Shakespeare, as it was Acted at
                  Reading School for the Subscription to the Naval Pillar, to be Erected in Honor of
                  the Naval Victories of the Present War </li>
               <li>King Lear</li>
               <li>Political and Literary Anecdotes of His Own Times.</li>
               <li>L’Allegro</li>
               <li>The Legend of Good Women</li>
               <li>Letters to R[ichard] Heber, Esq., containing critical remarks on the series of
                  novels beginning with "Waverley" and an attempt to ascertain their author </li>
               <li>Lamia, Isabella, The Eve of St. Agnes, and Other Poems</li>
               <li>Macbeth</li>
               <li>Mahomet (1741)</li>
               <li>The Maid’s Tragedy</li>
               <li>Manfred</li>
               <li>Marino Faliero</li>
               <li>Marmion: A Tale of Flodden Field</li>
               <li>Marriage: A Novel</li>
               <li>Measure for Measure</li>
               <li>La Médecine de l’esprit</li>
               <li>Melincourt</li>
               <li>Melmoth the Wanderer: A Tale</li>
               <li>The Merchant of Venice</li>
               <li>Merope</li>
               <li>The Merry Wives of Windsor</li>
               <li>Metamorphōseōn librī ["Books of Transformations"]</li>
               <li>Minstrelsy of the Scottish Border: Consisting of Historical and Romantic Ballads,
                  Collected in the Southern Counties of Scotland; with a Few of Modern Date, Founded
                  upon Local Tradition </li>
               <li>Mirandola</li>
               <li>Miscellany Poems, in two parts. Containing new translations of Virgil’s Eclogues,
                  Ovid’s Love-elegies, several parts of Virgil’s Æneids, Lucretius, Theocritus,
                  Horace, &amp;c. With several original poems, never before printed. </li>
               <li>The Miseries of Human Life, Or the Last Groans of Timothy Testy and Samuel
                  Sensitive; with a few supplementary sighs from Mrs. Testy. With which are now for
                  the first time Interspersed, Varieties, Incidental to the Principal Matter, In
                  Prose and Verse. In Nine Additional Dialogues, as Overheard by James Beresford,
                  A.M. Fellow of Merton-College, Oxford </li>
               <li>The Monastery</li>
               <li>The Fatal Revenge; or, the Family of Montorio</li>
               <li>A View of Society and Manners in Italy: with Anecdotes relating to some Eminent
                  Characters </li>
               <li>Much Ado About Nothing</li>
               <li>Mémoires pour servir à l’histoire de la vie privée, du retour, et du règne de
                  Napoléon </li>
               <li>Narrative Poems on the Female Character in the Various Relations of Human Life </li>
               <li>The New Testament</li>
               <li>Nightmare Abbey</li>
               <li>Northanger Abbey</li>
               <li>O’Donnel: A National Tale</li>
               <li>The Odyssey</li>
               <li>Oedipus Tyrranus</li>
               <li>Old Mortality</li>
               <li>The Old Testament</li>
               <li>On Reading a Ballad of Wordsworth </li>
               <li>Orestes in Argos; a Tragedy in Five Acts, by the late Peter Bayley, Esq. </li>
               <li>Orestes</li>
               <li>Harrington, A Tale, and Ormond, A Tale. In Three Volumes. Vol.I</li>
               <li>Othello</li>
               <li> Otto of Wittelsbach: A Tragedy</li>
               <li>Our Village: Sketches of Rural Character and Scenery [vol. 1]</li>
               <li>Our Village, 3rd edition</li>
               <li>"Our Village"[first draft story/sketch version]</li>
               <li>Our Village</li>
               <li>Paradise Lost</li>
               <li>Reliques of Ancient English Poetry, consisting of Old Heroic Ballads, Songs, and
                  other Pieces of our Earlier Poets, Together with Some of Later Date </li>
               <li>The Adventures of Peregrine Pickle, In Which are Included Memoirs of a Lady of
                  Quality </li>
               <li>Persuasion</li>
               <li>Peter Bell: A Lyrical Ballad</li>
               <li>Peter’s Letters to his Kinsfolk</li>
               <li>Philaster</li>
               <li>Philoctetes</li>
               <li>Pizarro</li>
               <li>The Pleasures of Friendship: A Poem, in two parts (1810, rpt. 1812, 1818) </li>
               <li>Poems of Mr. John Milton both English and Latin, compos’d at several times </li>
               <li>Poems. 1 vol.</li>
               <li>Poems. 2nd edition. With considerable additions. 2 vols.</li>
               <li>Poems, Odes, Prologues, and Epilogues Spoken on Public Occasions at Reading
                  School. To Which is Added Some Account of the Lives of Rev. Mr. Benwell and Rev.
                  Dr. Butt </li>
               <li>Poems, Odes, Prologues, and Epilogues Spoken on Public Occasions at Reading
                  School. Second edition. </li>
               <li>An Epistle from Mr. Pope to Dr. Arbuthnot (1734)</li>
               <li>The Poetical Remains of the Late Dr. John Leyden, with Memoirs of his Life, by
                  the Rev. James Morton. </li>
               <li>Pride and Prejudice: A Novel</li>
               <li>Prometheus Chained</li>
               <li>Prometheus Bound</li>
               <li>The Queen’s Wake: a Legendary Poem</li>
               <li>Recollections and Reflections, Personal and Political, as Connected with Public
                  Affairs, During the Reign of George III </li>
               <li>Recollections of a Literary Life; or, Books, Places, and People 3 vols. </li>
               <li>The Revenge: a Tragedy</li>
               <li>Rhododaphne: Or, The Thessalian Spell: A Poem</li>
               <li>The Life and Death of Richard the Third</li>
               <li>Rienzi; a Tragedy, in Five Acts</li>
               <li>The Rival Sisters a Poem in Three Cantos</li>
               <li>The Life and Strange SurprizingAadventures of Robinson Crusoe, of York, Mariner:
                  Who lived eight and twenty years all alone in an un-inhabited Island on the coast
                  of America, near the mouth of the great river of Oroonoque; having been cast on
                  shore by shipwreck, wherein all the men perished but himself. With an account how
                  he was at last as strangely deliver’d by pyrates. Written by himself. </li>
               <li>Three months passed in the mountains east of Rome : during the year 1819 </li>
               <li>Rule a Wife and Have a Wife</li>
               <li>Book of Ruth</li>
               <li>The Sad Shepherd: Or, A Tale of Robin Hood, a Fragment</li>
               <li>Sadak and Kalasrade; or, The Waters of Oblivions. A Romantic Opera in Two Acts </li>
               <li>Self Control: A Novel</li>
               <li>Sir Francis Darrell; or, the Vortex. A Novel</li>
               <li>The Sketch Book of Geoffrey Crayon, Gent.</li>
               <li>The Monks and the Giants: Prospectus and Specimen of an Intended National Work;
                  Intended to Comprise the Most Interesting Particulars Relating to King Arthur and
                  his Round Table, by William and Robert Whistlecraft of Stow-Market, in Suffolk,
                  Harness and Collar Makers </li>
               <li>Poetical Introduction to the Study of Botany (1801)</li>
               <li>The Stranger</li>
               <li>Sun-Set</li>
               <li>Tartuffe</li>
               <li>Temora, an Ancient Epic Poem, in Eight Books: Together with Several Other Epic
                  Poems, Composed by Ossian the Son of Fingal. Translated from the Galic language,
                  by James Macpherson. </li>
               <li>The Tempest</li>
               <li>The Testament of Love</li>
               <li>Théâtre des Grecs</li>
               <li>The Two Foscari</li>
               <li>Tom Crib’s Memorial to Congress</li>
               <li>The History of Tom Jones, A Foundling</li>
               <li>Tom Thumb</li>
               <li>Twelfth Night</li>
               <li>Two Noble Kinsmen</li>
               <li>Intercepted Letters, or, the Twopenny Post-bag</li>
               <li>Undine: A Romance, translated from the German</li>
               <li>Valerius: A Roman Story</li>
               <li>Venice Preserv’d</li>
               <li>A Very Woman; or the Prince of Tarent</li>
               <li>The Vespers of Palermo: A Tragedy in Five Acts</li>
               <li>Virginius</li>
               <li>Vivian</li>
               <li>Sun-Set</li>
               <li>Wallace: or, The fight of Falkirk. A Metrical Romance</li>
               <li>Wallace: an historical tragedy in five acts</li>
               <li>Warbeck of Wolfstein</li>
               <li>Washington; or Liberty Restored. A Poem in Ten Books</li>
               <li>Watlington Hill; A Poem</li>
               <li>Waverley; or ’Tis Sixty Years Since</li>
               <li>An Inquiry into the Nature and Causes of the Wealth of Nations</li>
               <li>Wheel of Fortune</li>
               <li>Winter Nights; Or, Fire-side Lucubrations</li>
               <li>The Winter’s Tale</li>
               <li>William Tell</li>
               <li>The Woman Hater</li>
               <li>Women: Or Pour et Contre. A Tale</li>
               <li>The Works of Mary Russell Mitford: Prose and Verse; viz. Our village, Belford
                  Regis, Country Stories, Finden’s Tableaux, Foscari, Julian, Rienzi, Charles the
                  First </li>
               <li>The Works of the English Poets, from Chaucer to Cowpwer, with prefaces,
                  biographical and critical </li>
               <li>Zai’re (1732)</li>
            </ul>
         </li>
         <li>Scholarly Work on Mary Russell Mitford <ul>
               <li>The Correspondence of Mary Russell Mitford and Thomas Noon Talfourd (1821-1825) </li>
               <li>The Life of Mary Russell Mitford, Authoress of "Our Village," Etc, Related in a
                  Selection from Her Letters to Her Friends </li>
            </ul>
         </li>
         <li>Other Current and Relevant Scholarship <ul>
               <li>Banned!: A Review of Theatrical Censorship in Britain</li>
               <li>The Censorship of English Drama, 1824-1901</li>
               <li>Review: 55 Days</li>
               <li>Romantic Drama and Historical Hermeneutics</li>
            </ul>
         </li>
         <li>
            <ul>
               <li> Booth Alison Advisory Board </li>
               <li> Drayton Alexandra Ph.D. Consultant </li>
               <li> Algee-Hewitt Mark Consultant: Data Visualization Group Advisory Board </li>
               <li> Colombo Amy Editor </li>
               <li> Gates Amy L. Ph.D. Editor </li>
               <li>Aymee Lynn Woody Woody Aymee Lynn Research Assistant </li>
               <li>Annie Gill Gill Annie Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Stewart Brooke Ann Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Collins Younes Courtney Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Bolton Carol Advisory Board </li>
               <li> Parisian Catherine M. Consultant </li>
               <li> Cox Catherine S. Consultant </li>
               <li> Robinson David Consultant </li>
               <li> Birnbaum David J. Consultant: Data Visualization Group Advisory Board </li>
               <li> Hitt Daniel Consultant </li>
               <li> Schierenbeck Daniel Editor </li>
               <li> Saglia Diego Advisory Board </li>
               <li> Beshero-Bondar Elisa Principal Investigator and Technical Coordinator Founding
                  Editor </li>
               <li> Parsons Elaine Frantz Consultant </li>
               <li> Raisanen Elizabeth Ph.D. Drama Founding Editor </li>
               <li> Hood Eric Ph.D. Founding Editor </li>
               <li> Burwick Frederick Advisory Board </li>
               <li> Bondar Gregory Manuscript Archaeology Founding Editor </li>
               <li> Price Jordan Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Bawden John Ph.D Associate Professor of History Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Fish Julie Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Rovira James Ph.D. Editor </li>
               <li> Horanic Jonathan Michael Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Bourrier Karen Consultant </li>
               <li> Donovan-Condron Kellie Ph.D. Founding Editor Poetry </li>
               <li> Wilson Lisa M. Managing Editor Bibliography and Correspondence Founding Editor </li>
               <li> Hughes Megan Abigail Consultant </li>
               <li> Creech Melinda Consultant </li>
               <li> O’Donnell Molly C. Editor </li>
               <li> Zimmer Mary Erica Consultant: Data Visualization Group </li>
               <li> Klamer Melissa Editor </li>
               <li> Smith Martha Nell Advisory Board </li>
               <li> Murray M. Stephanie Consultant </li>
               <li> Joukovsky Nicholas Advisory Board </li>
               <li> Allard Olivia Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Duck Patricia M. Advisory Board </li>
               <li> Reed Quinton A. Research Assistant Consultant </li>
               <li> Parker Rebecca Jeanne Editor </li>
               <li> Nesvet Rebecca Ph.D. Founding Editor </li>
               <li>Sylvan Baker Baker Sylvan Research Assistant </li>
               <li>Susannah Ritchey Ritchey Susannah Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Webb Samantha Ph.D Professor of English Founding Editor Fiction </li>
               <li> Cantwell Sara Consultant </li>
               <li> Garrett Shekneko Research Assistant </li>
               <li>Sara Perry Perry Sara Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Courtney Shawntel Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Triplette Stacey Ph.D. Consultant </li>
               <li> Lombardi Thomas Consultant: Data Visualization Group </li>
               <li> Beck Temani Research Assistant </li>
            </ul>
         </li>
         <li>
            <ul>
               <li> Parker Ashante Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Calderwood Austin Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Murray Chelsie Research Assistant </li>
               <li> LaSalle Corie Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Huang Chi-Ya Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Beckman Ella Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Amos Gracia Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Lown Hailey Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Long Heather Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Sarsfield Heather Consultant </li>
               <li> Burwell Jaime Breanna Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Murphy Kristen Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Kohli Mehaque Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Paine Margo Research Assistant </li>
               <li> LoRusso Natalie Claire Consultant </li>
               <li> Hebert Nathaniel Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Sasu Perdita Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Tang Rebecca Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Harnish Tracy Lynn Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Hays Toni Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Barr William Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Sainbert Wilmina Research Assistant </li>
               <li> Xiong Robin Research Assistant </li>
            </ul>
         </li>
         <li>
            <ul>
               <li> Coles William Allan </li>
               <li> William Harness </li>
               <li> L’Estrange Alfred Guy Kingan </li>
               <li> Needham Francis R </li>
               <li>unknown</li>
               <li>unknown</li>
               <li>unknown</li>
               <li>unknown</li>
               <li> Roberts William James </li>
               <li> Watson Vera </li>
            </ul>
         </li>
         <li>Historical Persons <ul>
               <li> Giuseppe Acerbi Joseph AcerbiSignor Acerbi </li>
               <li> George Pownoll Adams General Sir Knight Commander of Hanover (KCH) General Sir
                  George Pownoll Adams, KCH </li>
               <li>Joseph Addison Addison Joseph </li>
               <li>John Leycester Adolphus Adolphus John Leycester </li>
               <li>Aeschylus</li>
               <li>Prince Albert of Saxe-Coburg and GothaAlbert Prince Consort Francis Albert
                  Augustus Charles Emmanuel House of Saxe-Coburg and Gotha </li>
               <li>Alexander I Pavlovich Aleksandr </li>
               <li> Alfieri Vittorio Count </li>
               <li>AlfredAlfred the GreatKing of England</li>
               <li>Sir William Allan Allan William Sir </li>
               <li> Anacreon </li>
               <li> Anne </li>
               <li> Annesley Francis </li>
               <li> Ludovico Arisoto </li>
               <li> Baring Alexander First Baron Ashburton </li>
               <li> John Aubrey </li>
               <li> Jane Austen </li>
               <li> Francis Bacon Sir Francis Bacon Viscount St. Alban knight Attorney General of
                  England and Wales Lord Chancellor of England </li>
               <li> Baillie Joanna </li>
               <li>Robert Baldwin</li>
               <li> Bannister John Jack </li>
               <li> Barrett Browning Barrett Moulton-Barrett Elizabeth Elizabeth BarrettElizabeth
                  Barrett Browning </li>
               <li>Sir John Barrow Barrow John </li>
               <li>Mrs. Bayley</li>
               <li>Peter Bayley Peter Bayley </li>
               <li> Beaumont Francis </li>
               <li> Beaumont George Howland Sir Seventh Baronet member of Parliament for Bere Alston </li>
               <li> William Beechey Sir William BeecheyMember of the Royal Academy </li>
               <li> John Bellamy </li>
               <li>The Honourable Henry Grey Bennet Bennet Henry Grey Member of Parliament for
                  Shrewsbury Fellow of the Royal Society Fellow of the Royal Geographic Society Grey
                  Bennet </li>
               <li> Bennett George John </li>
               <li> Bennett William Cox William Cox Bennett </li>
               <li> Bennoch Francis Esq. </li>
               <li> Berengaria of Navarre Queen Consort of England </li>
               <li> James Beresford </li>
               <li> Berchem Berghem Nicholaes Pieterszoon </li>
               <li> Elizabeth Hardwick Barley Cavendish St. Loe Talbot Countess of Shrewsbury Bess
                  of Hardwick </li>
               <li>Thomas Bewick Thomas Bewick </li>
               <li>William Bewick William Bewick </li>
               <li> Isaac John Bickerstaffe Bickerstaff </li>
               <li> Bint Hannah </li>
               <li> Morris Birkbeck </li>
               <li> William Blake </li>
               <li> Body Ann </li>
               <li> Body Richard </li>
               <li> Henry St. John Lord Bolinbroke1st Viscount Bolingbroke </li>
               <li> James Boswell 9th Laird of Auchinlek </li>
               <li> Bowles William Lisle </li>
               <li>John Bradshaw John Bradshaw Bradshawe </li>
               <li> Brent George </li>
               <li> Brent Joel </li>
               <li> Brent Eliza Brent Lizzy </li>
               <li>Roger Boyle, Lord Broghill Roger Boyle Lord Broghill Baron Boyle of Broghill 1st
                  Earl of Orrerey member of Parliament for Arundel </li>
               <li> Bromley William </li>
               <li>Miss Brooke Brooke </li>
               <li>Henry Peter Brougham1st Baron Brougham and VauxLord Chancellor</li>
               <li>Betsy Broughton</li>
               <li> Brown Benjamin </li>
               <li> Browne Thomas </li>
               <li> Robert Browning </li>
               <li>James Bruce of Kinnaird Bruce James </li>
               <li> Brumoy Pierre Father </li>
               <li> Alexander Brunton Minister, Church of Scotland Moderator of the General
                  Assembly, Church of Scotland Professor of Hebrew and Oriental Languages,
                  University of Edinburgh Professor Very Reverend Alexander Brunton, D.D. </li>
               <li> Mary Balfour Brunton </li>
               <li> Marcus Junius Brutus </li>
               <li>Frederick Bulley Bulley Frederick </li>
               <li> Bullock William </li>
               <li>Sir Francis Burdett Burdett Francis Sir 5th Baronet of Bramcote member of
                  Parliament </li>
               <li>Mr. Burgess</li>
               <li> Edmund Burke </li>
               <li> Frances BurneyMadamed’Arblay </li>
               <li> Sarah Harriet Burney Miss Burney </li>
               <li> Robert Burns </li>
               <li>Butler</li>
               <li> Samuel Butler </li>
               <li> Byron George Gordon Noel sixth Baron Byron </li>
               <li> Annabella Anne Isabella Milbanke Noel Byron Baroness ByronBaroness
                  WentworthBaroness Noel-ByronA. I. Noel Byron </li>
               <li>Thomas Campbell</li>
               <li>George Canning George Canning Member of Parliament Prime Minister of the United
                  Kingdom Chancellor of the Exchequer Secretary of State for Foreign Affairs Leader
                  of the House of Commons President of the Board of Control Leader of the House of
                  Commons Treasurer of the Navy </li>
               <li> John Cartwright Royal Navy officerMajor, Nottinghamshire militia </li>
               <li> Robert Stewart Lord Castlereagh 2nd Marquess of Londonderry Secretary of State
                  for Foreign Affairs Leader of the House of Commons Secretary of State for War and
                  the Colonies President of the Board of Control Chief Secretary for Ireland </li>
               <li> MigueldeCervantes Saavedra Don Miguel de Cervantes Saavedra </li>
               <li> Alexander Chalmers </li>
               <li> Francis Legatt Chantrey </li>
               <li>Charles Spencer Charles Spencer </li>
               <li> Charles Spencer-Churchill Lord Charles Spencer-Churchill Member of Parliament </li>
               <li> Charles Stuart Charles I King of England, Scotland, France and Ireland, Defender
                  of the Faith, etc. </li>
               <li> Charles Stuart Charles II King of England, Scotland, France and Ireland,
                  Defender of the Faith, etc. </li>
               <li>Edward Chatfield Edward Chatfield </li>
               <li> Geoffrey Chaucer </li>
               <li> Chorley Fothergill Henry </li>
               <li> Jonathan Henry Christie John Henry Christie </li>
               <li> Meremoth? Clargo? </li>
               <li> Edward Daniel Clarke Dr. ClarkeProfessor of Mineralogy at Cambridge University </li>
               <li> Clarke William </li>
               <li> Pope Clement 6 Roger Pierre </li>
               <li> Member of Parliament for Oldham </li>
               <li>Mrs.Coffin </li>
               <li> Colburn Henry </li>
               <li> Coleridge Samuel Taylor </li>
               <li> Collins Thomas "little Collins" </li>
               <li> William Collins </li>
               <li>George Colman the Elder George Coleman George Colman the Elder </li>
               <li> Colman George the Younger the licenser </li>
               <li> Congreve William </li>
               <li>James Cook Cook James Captain </li>
               <li> Corneille Pierre </li>
               <li>Richard Cosway Cosway Richard member of the Royal Academy </li>
               <li> Harriot Mellon Coutts Beauclerk,Duchess of St. Albans </li>
               <li> Thomas Coutts </li>
               <li>Hannah Cowley Parkhouse Cowley Hannah </li>
               <li> William Cowper </li>
               <li> Francis Cowslade Frank Frank Cowslade </li>
               <li> William Coxe Master of Arts Fellow of the Royal Society Fellow of the Society of
                  Antiquaries Archdeacon of Wilts </li>
               <li> John Marten Cripps </li>
               <li> John Wilson Croker Member of Parliament </li>
               <li> George Croly </li>
               <li> Cromwell Oliver Lord Protector of the Commonwealth of England, Scotland, and
                  Ireland Member of Parliament for Cambridge Member of Parliament for Huntingdon </li>
               <li> Henry Cromwell Henry Cromwell Lord Lieutenant of Ireland Chancellor of Trinity
                  College, Dublin </li>
               <li> Cropp Elizabeth Croppy </li>
               <li>Mr. Crowther </li>
               <li>William Alleyne Culpeper William Alleyne Culpeper </li>
               <li>Martha Carteretta Cornelia Valpy Straker Culpeper Valpy Straker Culpeper Martha
                  Carteretta Cornelia Mrs. Culpepper </li>
               <li> Cumberland Richard </li>
               <li> d’Aubigné Françoise Marquise de Maintenon Madame Scarron </li>
               <li>R.C. Dallas Dallas Robert Charles Sir PC (Her Majesty’s Most Honourable Privy
                  Council) SL (Serjeant-at-Law) KC (King’s Counsel) MP (Member of Parliament) </li>
               <li> DurantedegliAlighieri DanteDante Alighieri </li>
               <li>Daphne</li>
               <li> Harvey Davenport Mary Ann </li>
               <li> Davie William Three Mile Cross </li>
               <li> Pierre Alexandre Édouard Fleury deChaboulon </li>
               <li> Daniel Defoe </li>
               <li>Stéphanie Félicité de Genlis Stéphanie Félicité du Crest de Saint-Aubin Comtesse
                  de GenlisMadame de Genlis </li>
               <li>Jean de Joinville Jean de Joinville knight </li>
               <li> Dekker Thomas </li>
               <li>Freidrich de la Motte Friedrich Heinrich Karl de la Motte Baron Fouqué </li>
               <li> de Quincey Thomas </li>
               <li>Germaine de Staël Anne Louise Germaine Necker de Staël-Holstein Madame de Staël </li>
               <li>Thomas John Dibdin Dibdin Thomas John </li>
               <li> Dickinson Charles Mr. Dickinson </li>
               <li> Dickinson Frances Vikris </li>
               <li>Grandmama Dickinson</li>
               <li>Mrs. Dickinson Catherine Allingham Dickinson </li>
               <li>Dickinson Nurse</li>
               <li>Mrs. Dobbs Dobbs </li>
               <li> Foscari Doge </li>
               <li> Donato Senator </li>
               <li>Andrea Doria Andrea Doria D’Oria </li>
               <li> Nathan Drake Dr. DrakeNathan Drake, M.D. </li>
               <li> Drover James </li>
               <li> Drover </li>
               <li> Drover </li>
               <li> Drover </li>
               <li> Drover </li>
               <li>William Drummond Drummond William Drummond of Hawthornden </li>
               <li> Dryden John </li>
               <li>James Graham, Marquess of Graham Graham James Marquess of Graham Duke of Montrose </li>
               <li> William George Spencer Cavendish 6th Duke of Devonshire Marquess of Hartington
                  Lord Chamberlain of the Household Licenser of Plays President of Royal
                  Horticultural Society Lord Lieutenant of Derbyshire </li>
               <li> Dukinfield Henry Duckinfield </li>
               <li>Maria Rebecca Davison, née Duncan Davison Duncan Maria Rebecca Miss DuncanMrs.
                  Davison </li>
               <li> Charles Dundas 1st Baron Amesbury Member of Parliament for Berkshire </li>
               <li> Edgeworth Maria </li>
               <li> Elizabeth Elford Adams </li>
               <li> Elford Adams Elizabeth </li>
               <li> Grace Chard Elford Miss Elford </li>
               <li> Elford Jonathan Member of Parliament for Westbury </li>
               <li> Charlotte Wynne Elford Mrs. Elford </li>
               <li> Hall Walrond Elford Elizabeth Mrs. Elford </li>
               <li> Elford Davies Mary Mrs. Elford </li>
               <li>Sir William ElfordSir William Elford, F.R.S., F.L.S., M.P. Elford William Sir
                  baronet Recorder for Plymouth Recorder for Totnes Member of Parliament for
                  Plymouth Member of Parliament for Rye Fellow of the Royal Society (FRS) Fellow of
                  the Linnaean Society (FLS) </li>
               <li> Elizabeth Tudor Queen Elizabeth I Queen of England, France and Ireland, Defender
                  of the Faith, etc. </li>
               <li>Sir Henry Ellis Ellis Henry </li>
               <li>Robert Elliston Elliston Robert William </li>
               <li> Emery John </li>
               <li>Ozoro Esther Esther </li>
               <li>Euripides</li>
               <li> Thomas Fairfax 3rd Lord Fairfax of Cameron Lord General of the New Model Army
                  Member of Parliament for West Riding Member of Parliament for Yorkshire </li>
               <li> Fawcett John Mr. Fawcett </li>
               <li> Henry Bradshaw Fearon </li>
               <li>Ferdinand I King of the Two Sicilies Ferdinand IV King of Naples King of Sicily </li>
               <li>Ferdinand VII King of Spain King of Spain </li>
               <li> Susan Edmonstone Ferrier </li>
               <li> Fielding Henry Henry FieldingScriblerus Secundus </li>
               <li> Giovanni Luigi Fieschi Fiesco count of Lavagna </li>
               <li> John Fisher Bishop of ExeterBishop of Salisbury </li>
               <li> Fitzharris Mr. Fitzharris </li>
               <li> Fletcher John </li>
               <li>Flush</li>
               <li>Maria Foote Stanhope Foote Maria </li>
               <li> Foote Samuel </li>
               <li> Captain Forbes </li>
               <li> Ford John </li>
               <li>Jacopo Foscari Foscari Jacopo </li>
               <li> Charles James Fox The Honourable Member of Parliament Leader of the House of
                  Commons secretary of State for Foreign Affairs </li>
               <li> Henry Richard Vassal Fox 3rd Baron Holland, of Holland3rd Baron Holland, of
                  Foxley, PCRight Honourable Lord Holland, PC </li>
               <li>Mrs. Frankland Frankland </li>
               <li> Benjamin Franklin </li>
               <li> Porden Franklin Eleanor Anne </li>
               <li> Sir John Franklin Royal Navy Fellow of the Royal Geographical Society
                  Rear-Admiral Lieutenant-Governor of Van Dieman’s Land, now Tasmania </li>
               <li>J.H. Frere Frere John Hookham Whistlecraft </li>
               <li> Jean Froissart canon of Chimay, France </li>
               <li> Henry Fuseli Johann Heinrich Füssli </li>
               <li> Fuseli Rawlins Sophia </li>
               <li> Garrick David </li>
               <li>Gaston II count of Foix </li>
               <li>Gaston III count of Foix Fébus </li>
               <li> George Spencer-Churchill 6th Duke of Marlborough Member of Parliament Lord
                  Lieutenant of Oxfordshire </li>
               <li>George III George William Frederick King of Great Britain and King of Ireland
                  King of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland </li>
               <li>George IV King of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland George Augustus
                  Frederick Prince Regent </li>
               <li> George </li>
               <li>Edward Gibbon Gibbon Edward Member of Parliament </li>
               <li>William Gifford Gifford William </li>
               <li>William Godwin William Godwin </li>
               <li> Oliver Goldsmith </li>
               <li> Goodchild Joseph </li>
               <li> Maria, Lady Callcott Callcott Graham Dundas Maria </li>
               <li> Thomas Gray </li>
               <li> Richard Griffin 2nd Baron Braybrooke Lord Braybrooke </li>
               <li>Lord Grey of Groby Grey Stamford Thomas Lord Grey of Groby Earl of Stamford </li>
               <li>Teresa Guiccioli Guiccioli Teresa Contessa </li>
               <li> John Gutch </li>
               <li>Sir Henry St John Halford Halford Henry St John Sir baronet Vaughn Henry </li>
               <li> Hamilton Samuel </li>
               <li> George Frideric Handel George Frederick Handel Georg Friedrich Händel </li>
               <li> John Hanson </li>
               <li> Mary Anne Hanson Portsmouth Lady PortsmouthCountess of Portsmouth </li>
               <li>Mary Harness Harness Mary </li>
               <li> Henry Harris </li>
               <li>Thomas Harrison Thomas Harrison </li>
               <li> Hatch John </li>
               <li> Havard, William William Havard </li>
               <li>General Hawley</li>
               <li>Mr. Hawley</li>
               <li>Nathaniel Hawthorne Nathaniel Hawthorne </li>
               <li> Franz Joseph Hadyn Joseph Haydn </li>
               <li> Haydon Benjamin Robert </li>
               <li>Benjamin Robert Haydon Haydon Robert Benjamin </li>
               <li>Mrs. Sarah Haydon Cobley Haydon Sarah </li>
               <li>Mary HymanMary Haydon Haydon Hyman Cawse Mrs. Haydon Mary </li>
               <li>William Hazlitt Hazlitt William </li>
               <li> Thomas Hearne Thomas Hearn </li>
               <li> Heath Charles Theodosius </li>
               <li> Heath James </li>
               <li>Richard Heber Heber Richard Member of Parliament for Oxford University </li>
               <li>Felicia Hemans Hemans Browne Felicia </li>
               <li>Henry V Harry Henry Plantagenet King of England and of France and Lord of Ireland </li>
               <li>Henry VI King of England and of France and Lord of Ireland King of England, Heir
                  and Regent of France and Lord of Ireland </li>
               <li> Frederick William Hervey Lord Hervey 5th Earl of Bristol Marquess of Bristol </li>
               <li> Hessey James Augustus J. A. Hessey </li>
               <li> Hill Charles </li>
               <li> Hill Sweatser Lucy </li>
               <li> Thomas Hobbes </li>
               <li>John Cam Hobhouse John Cam Hobhouse 1st Baron Broughton </li>
               <li> Hofland Wreaks Barbara </li>
               <li>Thomas Christopher Hofland Hofland Thomas Christopher </li>
               <li>William Hogarth Hogarth William </li>
               <li> Hogg James the Ettrick Shepherd </li>
               <li>Thomas Holcroft Thomas Holcroft </li>
               <li>Dr. Holden Holden Henry </li>
               <li> Margaret Holford Hodgson Miss HolfordMargaret Hodgson </li>
               <li> Holton Paul </li>
               <li>Homer</li>
               <li>Thomas Hood Hood Thomas </li>
               <li>Horace Quintus Horatius Flaccus </li>
               <li> John Howard </li>
               <li> Robert Sir Robert Howard Howard </li>
               <li>Thomas Howard Thomas Howard fourth duke of Norfolk </li>
               <li>Howard Brenton Howard Brenton </li>
               <li>Hugh Peters Hugh Peters </li>
               <li> Hugo Victor </li>
               <li> David Hume David Hume </li>
               <li>Joseph Hume Hume Joseph </li>
               <li> James Henry Leigh Hunt Leigh Hunt </li>
               <li> Robert Hunt </li>
               <li> Sir Richard Ingoldsby Richard, Lord Ingoldsby Richard Ingoldsby </li>
               <li>Henry Ireton Henry Ireton </li>
               <li> Washington Irving Geoffrey Crayon </li>
               <li>Mr. Jackson Jackson Mr. </li>
               <li> James Emily </li>
               <li>Miss JamesElizabeth Mary James Elizabeth Mary James </li>
               <li> Haycock James Susan Susannah Mrs. James </li>
               <li> James Francis Edward Stuart Prince of Walesthe Pretenderthe old Pretender </li>
               <li>Susan James James Susan Susy Deane </li>
               <li>James I</li>
               <li>James II King of England and Ireland James VII King of Scotland </li>
               <li> Jerrold Douglas William </li>
               <li>Jesus</li>
               <li>John the ApostleJohn the EvangelistSaint John</li>
               <li> Johnson, Samuel Samuel Johnson </li>
               <li> Johnson Miss Johnson </li>
               <li> Johnson John John Johnson, esq.Mr. Johnsonthe Junius of MarlowTimothy Trueman </li>
               <li> Johnson </li>
               <li> Johnstone John Jack </li>
               <li> Jones Thomas </li>
               <li>Ben Jonson Benjamin Jonson </li>
               <li> Jordan Dorothea </li>
               <li>Gaius Julius Caesar</li>
               <li> Lucius Junius Brutus JuniusConsul of the Roman Republic </li>
               <li> Kean Edmund </li>
               <li> Keats John </li>
               <li> Keep Harriet </li>
               <li> Keep? William </li>
               <li> Kemble Charles </li>
               <li>Frances Anne Kemble Kemble Frances Anne Fanny Fanny Kemble </li>
               <li>John Phillip Kemble Kemble John Phillip </li>
               <li>Maria Therese de Camp Kemble Kemble de Camp Maria Therese Mrs. Charles KembleMiss
                  deCamp </li>
               <li> Ralph Kettle Dr. Ralph Kettle Head of Trinity College </li>
               <li> William King Dr. William KingWilliam King, LL.D., Principal of St. Mary’s Hall,
                  Oxford </li>
               <li> Kirby Benjamin Ben </li>
               <li> Kirby Joseph </li>
               <li>James Sheridan Knowles Knowles James Sheridan </li>
               <li>August von Kotzebue von Kotzebue August </li>
               <li>, Anne, Lady Fairfax Anne Vere Fairfax </li>
               <li> Ponsonby Lamb Caroline Lady </li>
               <li> Lamb Charles </li>
               <li>Mary Lamb Lamb Mary </li>
               <li> Landon Maclean Laetitia Elizabeth </li>
               <li>William Lane Lane William </li>
               <li>Johann Kaspar Lavater Lavater Johann Kaspar </li>
               <li> Antoine Le Camus </li>
               <li> Lediard John </li>
               <li> Nathaniel Lee </li>
               <li> Lewington &gt;Mr. Lewington </li>
               <li>William Thomas Lewis Lewis William Thomas </li>
               <li> John Leyden </li>
               <li> Liston John </li>
               <li> Liston Tyrer Sarah Sarah ListonMrs. John ListonMiss TyrerSarah Tyrer </li>
               <li>Mr. Lock Lock Edward Mr. Lock </li>
               <li> Lockhart John Gibson John Gibson Lockhart </li>
               <li> Claude Lorrain Claude Gellée, dit le Lorrain </li>
               <li>Lucetti</li>
               <li>Sir George Macartney Macartney George </li>
               <li> James Macpherson Seumas MacMhuirichSeumas Mac a’ Phearsain </li>
               <li>Laetitia Macready Macready Laetitia </li>
               <li> Macready William </li>
               <li>Christopher Magnay Lord Mayor of London </li>
               <li>Mahomet</li>
               <li> Malton Mr. Malton </li>
               <li>Margaret of Anjou Margaret Marguerite de Anjou Queen Consort of England </li>
               <li>Tecla Mariam or Haseb Nanya Mariam </li>
               <li> Maria Antonia Josepha Johanna Marie AntoinetteQueen of France Archduchess Maria
                  Antonia of Austria Dauphine of France Queen consort of France and NavarreQueen
                  consort of the French </li>
               <li> Marlowe Christopher </li>
               <li> John Marriott Rev. John Marriott, A.M. </li>
               <li>Mr. Marriott</li>
               <li> Marsham Robert </li>
               <li> Martin Lucy </li>
               <li>Mary II Sovereign of England, Scotland, and Ireland </li>
               <li>Queen Mary Mary Stuart </li>
               <li> Massinger Philip </li>
               <li>Mast</li>
               <li>William Henry West Betty Master Betty </li>
               <li> Matthews George </li>
               <li> Charles Maturin </li>
               <li>Mr. Maurice</li>
               <li>James May</li>
               <li> May William </li>
               <li>John McLeod McLeod/MacLeod John </li>
               <li>Herman Melville Melville Herman </li>
               <li> Merry William Esquire </li>
               <li>Ras Michael</li>
               <li>MichelangeloMichelangelo di Lodovico Buonarroti Simoni Simoni Michelangelo di
                  Lodovico Buonarroti </li>
               <li>Gilbert MillingtonGilbert Myllington Gilbert Millington Member of Parliament for
                  Nottingham </li>
               <li>Henry Hart Milman</li>
               <li> Milton, John John Milton </li>
               <li>Miranda</li>
               <li> George Mitford Esq. George Midford </li>
               <li>Molière Poquelin Jean-Baptiste </li>
               <li> John Berkeley Monck </li>
               <li> Mary Stephens Monck Mrs. Monck </li>
               <li>Sir Edward Montagu, Earl of Sandwich Edward Montagu </li>
               <li> Montague </li>
               <li> Mary Wortley Pierrepont Montague Lady Mary Wortley Montague </li>
               <li> Moore John M.D. </li>
               <li> Thomas Moore </li>
               <li>Hannah More More Hannah </li>
               <li> George Howard Viscount Morpeth 6th Earl of Carlisle (third creation) Lord Privy
                  Seal under George IV and Canning Lord Privy Seal under William IV and Melbourne </li>
               <li> Morton Thomas </li>
               <li> Mossy </li>
               <li> Johannes Chrysostomus Wolfgangus Theophilus Mozart Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart </li>
               <li> Mitford Mary Russell </li>
               <li> </li>
               <li> Hall </li>
               <li>Robert Mudie</li>
               <li>Joseph Shepherd Munden Munden Joseph Shepherd </li>
               <li> John Murray II </li>
               <li> Bonaparte Napoleon </li>
               <li>Horatio Nelson Nelson Horatio Admiral 1st Viscount Nelson 1st Duke of Bronté
                  Royal Navy </li>
               <li> Jacob Newberry </li>
               <li> Newman </li>
               <li> John Nicholls </li>
               <li> Nicholson Jeremiah </li>
               <li> Nicholson unknown </li>
               <li> Nooth Charlotte </li>
               <li> Northmore Thomas </li>
               <li> O’Hara Kane </li>
               <li> O’Keefe O’Keeffe John </li>
               <li> O’Neill Elizabeth </li>
               <li>Mary Ann Orger Orger Ivers Mary Ann </li>
               <li> Otway Thomas </li>
               <li> Publius Ovidius Naso Ovid </li>
               <li> Sydney Owenson Lady Morgan </li>
               <li>Charles Fyshe Palmer Palmer Charles Fyshe Long Fyshe </li>
               <li>Madelina Gordon Sinclair Palmer Palmer Sinclair Gordon Madelina Madalina the Lady
                  Lady M.P.Lady Mad.Lady Madelina Palmer </li>
               <li> HenryJohn Temple Palmerston Viscount Henry John Temple Palmerston Prime Minister
                  of the United Kingdom </li>
               <li> Joseph Parfitt </li>
               <li> Sarah Parfitt </li>
               <li> Peter George Patmore </li>
               <li> Patty More research needed. </li>
               <li> Payn Mr. Payn </li>
               <li> Thomas Love Peacock </li>
               <li>Robert Peel Robert Peel Sir Robert Peel Prime Minister of the United Kingdom </li>
               <li> William Herbert 1st Earl of Pembroke, tenth creation 1st Baron Herbert of
                  Cardiff </li>
               <li> Thomas Percy chaplain to George III Dean of Carlisle Cathedral Bishop of Dromore </li>
               <li> Petrarca Francesco Petrarch </li>
               <li>Mr. Philips</li>
               <li> Charles Phillips </li>
               <li> Christopher Pitt </li>
               <li> George Pitt 2nd Baron Rivers Member of Parliament </li>
               <li> William Pitt The Honourable William PittWilliam Pitt the youngerPrime Minister
                  of the United KingdomPrime Minister of Great BritainChancellor of the Exchequer </li>
               <li> Pope Pius VII Chiaramonti Barnaba Niccolò Maria Luigi </li>
               <li>Pliny the elder</li>
               <li> Thomas Plumer Sir Thomas Plumer Vice Chancellor of England Master of the Rolls </li>
               <li>Plutarch</li>
               <li> Poole John </li>
               <li> Pope Alexander </li>
               <li> Pope Jane </li>
               <li>L’AllegraAnna Maria Porter Porter Anna Maria </li>
               <li>John Charles Walopp Portsmouth3rd Earl of PortsmouthLord PortsmouthViscount
                  Lymington</li>
               <li>The Three Mile Cross postman (in 1821)</li>
               <li>Robert Potter Potter Robert Rev. Potter Rev. Robert Potter </li>
               <li> Praed Winthrop </li>
               <li> Price Stephen </li>
               <li>Elizabeth Stuart Elizabeth Stuart </li>
               <li> Bryan Waller Procter Barry Cornwall </li>
               <li> Luigi Pulci </li>
               <li>Mr. QuayleMr. Quale</li>
               <li> Queen Anne </li>
               <li>Caroline Queen Consort of the United Kingdom Caroline of BrunswickCaroline Amelia
                  Elizabeth of Brunswick-Wolfenbüttel Princess of Wales </li>
               <li> Racine Jean-Baptiste </li>
               <li> Radcliffe Ward Ann </li>
               <li> Walter Raleigh Sir Walter Raleigh </li>
               <li>RaphaelRaffaello Sanzio da Urbino</li>
               <li> Rapley John Jack </li>
               <li> Rapley John </li>
               <li> Reeve Mrs. Reeve </li>
               <li>Rembrandt van Rijn Harmenszoon Rembrandt </li>
               <li> John Hamilton Reynolds </li>
               <li> Richard I King of England Duke of Normandy Duke of Aquitaine Count of Anjou </li>
               <li>Richard the 2ndRichard IIKing of EnglandLord of IrelandDuke of Aquitaine</li>
               <li>Richard III King of England Richard of Gloucester </li>
               <li> Henry Kemp Richardson </li>
               <li> Samuel Richardson </li>
               <li>Cola di Rienzo Tribune of Rome </li>
               <li> William Horace Pitt-Rivers 3rd Baron Rivers, fourth creation Horace Beckford </li>
               <li>William Robertson William Robertson Fellow of the Royal Society of Edinburgh
                  Fellow of the Society of Antiquaries of Scotland Doctor of Divinity minister of
                  the Church of Scotland King’s Chaplain Chaplain of Stirling Castle Principal of
                  the University of Edinburgh </li>
               <li> Robins George Henry </li>
               <li> Robinson Henry Crabb </li>
               <li> Samuel Rogers </li>
               <li>Jean-Jacques Rousseau Jean-Jacques Rousseau </li>
               <li>Fanny RowdenMrs. Rowden Rowden St. Quentin Frances Arabella </li>
               <li>Mary Valpy RoworthMiss Valpy Valpy Roworth Mary Ann Catherine </li>
               <li> Peter Paul Rubens Sir </li>
               <li> Rachel Wriothesley Russell Rachel Wriothesley, Lady Russell </li>
               <li> Mitford Russell Mary Mrs. Mitford </li>
               <li> Russell Dicker Mary Mrs. Russell </li>
               <li> Russell Richard Reverend Dr. Rev. Dr. Richard Russell </li>
               <li>John Towill Rutt Rutt John Towill </li>
               <li> Charles Sackville 6th Earl of Dorset1st Earl of Middlesex </li>
               <li>William Cecil, Lord Salisbury William Cecil </li>
               <li>William Say William Say </li>
               <li>Johann Christoph Friedrich von Schiller von Schiller Johann Christoph Friedrich </li>
               <li> John Scott John Scott </li>
               <li> John Scott 1st Earl of Eldon Lord Chancellor of Great Britain </li>
               <li> Scott, Walter Walter Scott </li>
               <li>Catherine Maria Sedgwick</li>
               <li> Selim </li>
               <li>Thomas James Serle</li>
               <li> Marie de Rabutin-Chantal de Sévigné Marquise de Sévigné Madame Sévigné </li>
               <li> Martha Seward </li>
               <li>Sforza</li>
               <li> Shakespeare William </li>
               <li> John Sheffield 1st Duke of Buckingham and Normanby Lord Mulgrave </li>
               <li>Mary Wollstonecraft Godwin Shelley</li>
               <li>Percy Bysshe Shelley Shelley Percy Bysshe </li>
               <li> Henry John Shepherd Member of Parliament for Shaftesbury </li>
               <li> Sheridan Richard Brinsley </li>
               <li> Sherwood Thomas </li>
               <li> Kemble Siddons Sarah </li>
               <li>Sir John Sinclair Sinclair John Sir baronet </li>
               <li> Skerrett Marianne </li>
               <li> Sloman </li>
               <li> Adam Smith Head of Moral Philosophy, the University of Glasgow Doctor of Laws
                  (LL.D.) Lord Rector of the University of Glasgow </li>
               <li>Horace Smith Smith Horace Smith Horatio </li>
               <li> Smollett, Tobias Tobias George Smollett </li>
               <li>George Soane</li>
               <li> George Soane G. Soane, A.B. </li>
               <li>Sophocles</li>
               <li> Robert Southey Poet Laureate of England </li>
               <li> Joseph Spence </li>
               <li>Edmund Spenser Edmund Spenser </li>
               <li>Sir George Staunton Staunton George </li>
               <li>Sir Richard Steele Steele Richard </li>
               <li>Thomas Wentworth, Earl of Strafford Thomas Wentworth </li>
               <li> Strong Elizabeth </li>
               <li> Strong George </li>
               <li> Dorothy Sidney Spencer Smythe Countess of SunderlandSacharissa </li>
               <li>Mr. Swan</li>
               <li> Jonathan Swift Dean of St Patrick’s Cathedral, Dublin Dean SwiftLemuel
                  GulliverIsaac BickerstaffM.B. Drapier </li>
               <li>George Talbot the Sixth Earl of Shrewsbury </li>
               <li>Rachael Rutt Talfourd Talfourd Rutt Rachel Mrs. Thomas Talfourd </li>
               <li>Thomas Noon Talfourd Talfourd Thomas Noon </li>
               <li>Francois Joseph Talma Talma Francois Joseph </li>
               <li> Tasso Torquato </li>
               <li>John Taylor</li>
               <li> Jeremy Taylor </li>
               <li> Taylor James Henry </li>
               <li>John Taylor</li>
               <li> Taylor Kerenhappuch K. </li>
               <li>Thomas James (T.J.) Thackeray</li>
               <li> Thelwall John </li>
               <li>Robert Tichborne Robert Tichborne </li>
               <li>Sir Matthew Tierney Tierney Matthew John Sir baronet </li>
               <li> Tindal Harrison Henrietta Euphemia Butler Diana </li>
               <li> Tiziano Vecelli Tiziano Vecellio Titian </li>
               <li> Tobin John </li>
               <li>James Traill</li>
               <li> Tubb Daniel Individual identified in the Shinfield parish register by Francis
                  Needham whose name may have been used by Mitfordfor several Our Village
                  characters, including "Dr. Tubb" . Source: Francis Needham, letter to William
                  Roberts, 16 January 1954, NeedhamPapers, Reading Central Library. </li>
               <li> Tully Miss Tully </li>
               <li> Valpy French Catherine Elizabeth Blanch </li>
               <li> Valpy Abraham John Abraham John Valpy </li>
               <li> Valpy </li>
               <li> Valpy French Penelope Arabella Penelope Arabella ValpyPenelope Valpy French </li>
               <li> Valpy Richard Doctor of Divinity (DD) Fellow of the Society of Antiquaries (FSA)
                  Dr. Valpy </li>
               <li>Sir John Vanbrugh Vanbrugh John </li>
               <li>Henry Vane Henry Vane </li>
               <li>Victoria Queen of the United Kingdom Empress of India Alexandrina Victoria
                  Hanover </li>
               <li> George Villiers 2nd Duke of Buckingham 20th Baron de Ros of Helmsley </li>
               <li>Mr. Vines</li>
               <li> Publius Vergilius Maro Virgil </li>
               <li> Voltaire François-Marie Arouet </li>
               <li> Wakefield Daniel </li>
               <li> Charles Edward Walker </li>
               <li> John Walker </li>
               <li> Edmund Waller </li>
               <li> Horace Walpole 4th Earl of Orford (second creation) Member of Parliament for
                  Callington Member of Parliament for Castle Rising Member of Parliament for King’s
                  Lynn </li>
               <li> Izaak Walton </li>
               <li> Prescott James Warde James Prescott WardeMr. Warde </li>
               <li> Warry Joseph </li>
               <li> George Washington General Washington President of the United States of America </li>
               <li> Watteau, Jean-Antoine Jean-Antoine Watteau </li>
               <li> Webb Eliza Elizabeth </li>
               <li> Webb James </li>
               <li> Webb Jane Eleanor Jane Eleanor Webb </li>
               <li> John Webb </li>
               <li> Webb Mary </li>
               <li> Webb Mary Elizabeth Mary Elizabeth Webb </li>
               <li> Webster John </li>
               <li> Wellesley Arthur Field Marshal First Duke of Wellington The Iron Duke </li>
               <li> Weyland John Mr. Weyland </li>
               <li> Whateley Elijah </li>
               <li> Kate Wheeler Miss Wheeler </li>
               <li> Gilbert White </li>
               <li>White kittenSelimaGrizzy</li>
               <li> Wilkie, William William Wilkie </li>
               <li>William III King of England and Ireland William II King of Scotland Stadtholder
                  Willem III van OranjeWilliam of OrangeKing Billy </li>
               <li>William IV King of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland, and King of
                  Hanover William Hanover </li>
               <li> Willis David </li>
               <li> Willis John </li>
               <li>Nathaniel Parker Willis Willis Nathaniel Parker </li>
               <li> Willis Thomas </li>
               <li> John Wilmot 2nd Earl of Rochester </li>
               <li> John Wilson John Wilson of Elleray, FRSE Professor of Moral Philosophy,
                  University of Edinburgh Christopher North </li>
               <li>Sir Robert Thomas Wilson Wilson Thomas Robert Sir </li>
               <li> Windsor "paper man" </li>
               <li>Dorothy Wordsworth</li>
               <li> Wordsworth William </li>
               <li>Charles Mayne Young Young Mayne Charles </li>
               <li> Edward Young </li>
               <li> Young Mr. Young </li>
            </ul>
         </li>
         <li>Archetypes <ul>
               <li>Ahab</li>
               <li>Amaziah</li>
               <li>Baal</li>
               <li> Bluebeard </li>
               <li>Cassandra </li>
               <li>CupidEros</li>
               <li>Deborah</li>
               <li>Prince Bedreddin Hassan</li>
               <li> Rapley Jack </li>
               <li>Jael</li>
               <li> Eusden James Jem </li>
               <li>Jezebel</li>
               <li>Jonah</li>
               <li>Judy</li>
               <li>LazarusLazarus of Bethany</li>
               <li> Fuller Master </li>
               <li> Nathan </li>
               <li>Prometheus</li>
               <li>PunchMr. Punch</li>
               <li>Pygmalion</li>
               <li> Rehoboam </li>
               <li> Satan </li>
               <li>Vesta</li>
            </ul>
         </li>
         <li>Fictional Characters <ul>
               <li>Abbé de L’Épée</li>
               <li>An Abbot</li>
               <li>Alberti</li>
               <li>Alfonso</li>
               <li>Alice</li>
               <li>Ambassador</li>
               <li>Annabel</li>
               <li> Annaly </li>
               <li> Annaly </li>
               <li>Antigone</li>
               <li>An Archbishop</li>
               <li> Ascanius </li>
               <li>Aspatia</li>
               <li>John Balfour</li>
               <li>Bardolph</li>
               <li>Beatrice</li>
               <li>Bellario (Euphrasia)</li>
               <li> Bennet Mrs. Bennet </li>
               <li>Berta</li>
               <li>Bertone</li>
               <li>Lord President Bradshaw</li>
               <li>Baron of Bradwardine</li>
               <li>Matthew Bramble</li>
               <li>Miss Branghton</li>
               <li>Mr. Briggs</li>
               <li> Dennis Brulgruddery </li>
               <li>Cafarello</li>
               <li>Calvi</li>
               <li> Donato Camilla </li>
               <li>Camilla</li>
               <li>Camillo</li>
               <li>Cantwell</li>
               <li> Catherine </li>
               <li>Celso</li>
               <li>Centinel</li>
               <li>Charles the First</li>
               <li>Sir Charles Grandison</li>
               <li>Clarissa</li>
               <li>Claudia</li>
               <li> Collins Mr. Collins </li>
               <li>Angelo Colonna</li>
               <li>Lady Colonna</li>
               <li>Stephen Colonna</li>
               <li>Constance</li>
               <li>Cook</li>
               <li>Coriolanus</li>
               <li> Donato Cosmo </li>
               <li>Oliver Cromwell</li>
               <li>Mr. Cypress</li>
               <li>Count D’Alba</li>
               <li>Dandie Dinmont</li>
               <li> Fitzwilliam Darcy Mr. Darcy </li>
               <li>The Dauphin</li>
               <li>Jeanie Deans</li>
               <li>Jenny Denison</li>
               <li>Desdemona</li>
               <li> Dido </li>
               <li>Dirk Hatteraick</li>
               <li>Dogberry</li>
               <li>Doge Foscari</li>
               <li>Don Quixote</li>
               <li> Donato Senator </li>
               <li>Dousterwivel</li>
               <li>Downes</li>
               <li>Camilla</li>
               <li> Dulcinea del Toboso </li>
               <li>Edie Ochiltree</li>
               <li>Elspeth</li>
               <li>Erizzo</li>
               <li>Lord Fairfax</li>
               <li>Falstaff</li>
               <li>Fiesco</li>
               <li> Ferdinando Flosky </li>
               <li> Foscari Francesco </li>
               <li>Frangipani</li>
               <li>Duke of Gloucester</li>
               <li> Lord Grizzle </li>
               <li>Miss Grizzy</li>
               <li>Hacker</li>
               <li>Hamlet</li>
               <li>Hammond</li>
               <li>Harrison</li>
               <li>Helen</li>
               <li>Hengo</li>
               <li> Henry </li>
               <li>Sir Thomas Herbert</li>
               <li>Hermione</li>
               <li>Camilla</li>
               <li>Imogen</li>
               <li>Ireton</li>
               <li> Isabella </li>
               <li>Isabella</li>
               <li>Miss Jacky</li>
               <li>Jailer</li>
               <li>Julian</li>
               <li>The Lord Chief Justice</li>
               <li>Katharine</li>
               <li> Corny </li>
               <li>King Philip</li>
               <li>Lady Fairfax</li>
               <li>Lady Singleton</li>
               <li> Michael Lambourne </li>
               <li>Laura</li>
               <li>Leanti</li>
               <li>Leontes</li>
               <li> Elizabeth Bennet Lizzy Bennet </li>
               <li>Lady Macbeth</li>
               <li>Lady MacLaughlan</li>
               <li>Sally Maggs</li>
               <li>Mr. Edgar Mandlebert</li>
               <li>Maritornes</li>
               <li>Marten</li>
               <li>Mary</li>
               <li>May-flower</li>
               <li>Mrs. M’Crule</li>
               <li>Meg Merrilies</li>
               <li>The Duke of Melfi</li>
               <li>Miranda</li>
               <li>Miss Crawley</li>
               <li>ModAntiquesBeau</li>
               <li>Dr. Peter Morris</li>
               <li> Mosse Elizabeth Mossy </li>
               <li>Mr. Dexter</li>
               <li>Mrs. MCrule</li>
               <li>Nerissa</li>
               <li>Miss Nicky</li>
               <li> Christopher North </li>
               <li>Nuncio</li>
               <li>Corporal Nym</li>
               <li>Miss O’Faley</li>
               <li>John Oldbuck</li>
               <li>Olivia</li>
               <li>Orestes</li>
               <li>Orestes</li>
               <li>Orlando de Boys de Boys Orlando </li>
               <li> Ormond Harry Protagonist of Ormond</li>
               <li>Ossian</li>
               <li>Othello</li>
               <li> Nicholson Mrs. Nicholson </li>
               <li>Paolo</li>
               <li>Paolo</li>
               <li>Penelope</li>
               <li>Penruddock</li>
               <li>Phaeton</li>
               <li> Pickle Peregrine </li>
               <li>Pierce</li>
               <li>Count Pisani</li>
               <li>Pleydell</li>
               <li>Polonius</li>
               <li>Pride</li>
               <li>Princess Elizabeth</li>
               <li>Prospero</li>
               <li>Queen Henrietta Maria</li>
               <li>Queen Dollalolla</li>
               <li>Gertrude, Queen of Denmark</li>
               <li>Aunt Rachel</li>
               <li>Rebecca</li>
               <li>Renzi</li>
               <li>Cola di Rienzi</li>
               <li>Rolla</li>
               <li>Rosa</li>
               <li>Rowena</li>
               <li>Lord Salisbury</li>
               <li> Sancho Panza </li>
               <li>Savelli</li>
               <li>Lord Say</li>
               <li> Sebastian </li>
               <li>Servant</li>
               <li>Sforza</li>
               <li>Mr. Smith</li>
               <li> Sophy </li>
               <li>Teresa</li>
               <li>Tichburn</li>
               <li>Timothy Trueman</li>
               <li> Count Ugolino </li>
               <li>Ulric</li>
               <li>Ursini</li>
               <li>Valore</li>
               <li>Sir Harry Vane</li>
               <li> Richard Varney </li>
               <li> Viola </li>
               <li>Volumnia</li>
               <li> Western Sophia </li>
               <li>the White Spirit</li>
               <li>Wolsey</li>
               <li>Count Zeno</li>
            </ul>
         </li>
      </ol>
   </body>
</html>
