<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div type="contents">
    <head>CONTENTS.</head>
    <list>
        <item>BOOK I.</item>
        <list>
            <item>CHAP. I. Departure.—Passage from Plymouth to Madeira.—Description of that Island, p. 1</item>
            <item>CHAP. II. The Passage from Madeira to the Cape Verd Islands, and from thence to the Cape of Good Hope, 19</item>
            <item>CHAP. III. Stay at the Cape of Good Hope.—Account of that Settlement, 39</item>
            <item>CHAP. IV. Run from the Cape to the Antarctic Circle; first Season spent in high Southern Latitudes.—Arrival on the Coast of New Zeeland, 57</item>
            <item>CHAP. V. Stay at Dusky Bay; Description of it, and Account of our Transactions there, 81</item>
            <item>CHAP. VI. Passage from Dusky Bay to Queen Charlotte’s Sound.—Junction with the Adventure.—Transactions during our Stay there, 124</item>
            <item>CHAP. VII. Run from New Zeeland to O-Taheitee, 152</item>
            <item>CHAP. VIII. Anchorage in O-Aitepeha Harbour, on the lesser Peninsula of O-Taheitee.—Account of our Stay there.—Removal to Madavaï Bay, 165</item>
            <item>CHAP. IX. Account of our Transactions at Matavaï Bay, 212</item>
            <item>CHAP. X. Account of our Transactions at the Society Islands, 242</item>
        </list>
        <item>BOOK II.</item>
        <list>
            <item>CHAP. I. Run from the Society Isles to the Friendly Isles, with an Account of our Transactions there, 274</item>
            <item>CHAP. II. Course from the Friendly Isles to New Zeeland.—Separation from the Adventure.—Second Stay in Queen Charlotte’s Sound, 316</item>
            <item>CHAP. III. The second Course towards the high Southern Latitudes; from New Zeeland to Easter Island, 346</item>
            <item>CHAP. IV. An Account of Easter Island, and our Stay there, 366</item>
            <item>CHAP. V. Run from Easter Island to the Marquesas.—Stay in Madre de Dios Harbour, on Waitahoo.Course from thence through the Low Islands to Taheitee, 397</item>
            <item>CHAP. VI. An Account of our second Visit to the Island of O-Taheitee, 430</item>
            <item>CHAP. VII. The second Stay at the Society Islands, 471</item>
            <item>CHAP. VIII. Run from the Society to the Friendly Islands, 500</item>
        </list>
        <item>BOOK III.</item>
        <list>
            <item>CHAP. I. An Account of our Stay at Mallicollo, and Discovery of the New Hebrides, 526</item>
            <item>CHAP. II. Account of our Stay at Tanna, and Departure from the New Hebrides, 568</item>
            <item>CHAP. III. Discovery of New Caledonia.—Account of our Stay there.—Range along the Coast to our Departure.—Discovery of Norfolk Island.—Return to New Zeeland, 644</item>
            <item>CHAP. IV. Third and last Stay at Queen Charlotte’s Sound in New Zeeland, 691</item>
            <item>CHAP. V. The Course from New Zeeland to Tierra del Fuego—Stay at Christmas Harbour, 712</item>
            <item>CHAP. VI. Stay at the New Year’s Islands.—Discovery of Lands to the Southward.—Return to the Cape of Good Hope, 733</item>
            <item>CHAP. VII. Second Stay at the Cape of Good Hope.—Run from thence to the Islands of St. Helena and Ascension, 757</item>
            <item>CHAP. VIII. Run from Ascension past the Island of Fernando da Noronha, to the Açores.—Stay at Fayal —Return to England, 777</item>
        </list>
    </list>
</div>

